you've studied the human mind cognition
你研究过人类的头脑认知
language vision evolution psychology
语言视觉进化心理学
from child to adult from the level of
从孩子到成人的水平
individual to the level of our entire
个人到我们整体的水平
civilization so I feel like I can start
文明， 所以我觉得我可以开始
with a simple multiple-choice question
有 一个简单的 多项选择题
what is the meaning of life is it a to
生命的意义是什么呢？
attain knowledge as Plato said B to
获得知识，因为柏拉图说B到
attain power as Nietzsche said C to
获得权力，因为尼采说C到
escape death as Ernest Becker said d to
难逃一死欧内斯特·贝克尔说 d至
propagate our genes as Darwin and others
传播我们的基因作为达尔文和其他人
have said e there is no meaning as the
说 ê 没有意义的
nihilists have said F knowing the
虚无主义者说F 知道了
meaning of life is beyond our cognitive
生命的意义 超出了我们的认知
capabilities as Steven Pinker said based
Steven Pinker所说的能力
on my interpretation twenty years ago
我二十年前的解释
and G none of the above
和G 以上都没有
I'd say aid comes closest but I would
我会说援助最接近，但我愿意
amend that to attaining not only
修改， 不仅要获得
knowledge but fulfillment more generally
知识， 但更普遍的履行
that is life health stimulation access
那是生命健康刺激的途径
to the living cultural and social world
对生活的文化和社会世界
now this is our meaning of life it's not
现在这是我们生命的意义，但事实并非如此
the meaning of life if you were to ask
如果你要问 ，生命 的 意义
our genes their meaning is to propagate
我们的基因的意义是 传播
copies of themselves but that is
他们自己的副本， 但那 是
distinct from the meaning that the brain
与大脑的意义截然不同
that they lead to sets for itself so to
他们导致自己这样做
you knowledge is a small subset or a
你的知识是一小部分 或一个
large subset it's a large subset but
大子集它是一个很大的子集但是
it's not the entirety of human striding
这不是整个人类的跨越
because we also want to interact with
因为我们也希望 与 互动
people we want to experience beauty we
我们想体验美的人
want to experience the the richness of
想体验的丰富性
the natural world but understanding the
自然界， 但理解
what makes the universe tick is his way
宇宙嘀嗒的原因是他的方式
up there for some of us more than others
在那里我们一些人比其他人更
certainly for me that's that's one of
对我来说当然是那个
the top five so is that a fundamental
前五名也是一个 根本
aspect are you just describing your own
你只是描述自己的方面
preference or is this a fundamental
偏好或这是一个 基本的
aspect of human nature is to seek
人性的一面是 寻求
knowledge just in your latest book you
知识就在你最新的书中
talk about the the the power the
谈谈对电力的
usefulness of rationality and reason so
理性 和理性的有用性
on is that a fundamental nature
这是一个基本的本质
human beings or is it something we
人类还是我们的东西
should just strive for it's both it is
应该只是争取 ，这既是它 是
we're capable of striving for it because
我们有能力争取它，因为
it is one of the things that make us
这是让我们成功的事情 之一
what we are Homo sapiens wise men we are
我们是 智人的智者我们是谁
unusual among animals in the degree to
动物之间的异常程度
which we acquire knowledge and use it to
我们获取知识 并将其用于
survive we we make tools we strike
幸存下来我们制造工具
agreements via language we extract
我们提取的语言协议
poisons we predict the behavior of
毒药我们预测 的行为
animals we try to get at the workings of
我们试图 了解 动物的动物
plants and when I say we I don't just
植物，当我说我们不只是
mean we in the modern West but we as a
意味着我们在现代西方社会，但我们作为一个
species everywhere which is how we've
到处都是物种，这就是我们的方式
managed to occupy every niche on the
设法占据了每一个利基市场
planet and how we've managed to drive
星球以及我们如何成功驾驶
other animals to extinction and the
其他动物灭绝和
refinement of Reason in pursuit of human
追求人性 的 理性 精炼
well-being of health happiness social
健康幸福社会的 福祉
richness cultural richness is our our
丰富的文化丰富是我们的
main challenge in the present that is
目前的主要挑战是
using our intellect using our knowledge
使用我们的知识运用我们的知识
to figure out how the world works how we
弄清楚 世界是如何运作的
work in order to make discoveries and
为了 使工作的发现和
strike agreements that make us all
达成协议，使我们所有人
better off in the long run right and you
从长远来看，你和你有更好的关系
do that almost undeniably and in a
几乎无可否认地做到这一点
data-driven way in a recent book but I'd
在最近的一本书中，数据驱动的方式，但我
like to focus on the artificial
喜欢专注于人工
intelligence aspect of things and not
事物的智力方面而不是
just artificial intelligence but natural
只是人工智能，但很自然
intelligence too so twenty years ago in
二十年前的情报也是如此
the book you've written on how the mind
你写的关于心灵的书
works
作品
you conjecture again my right to
你再次猜想我的权利
interpret things you could you can
你可以解释的事情
correct me if I'm wrong but you
如果我错了你，请纠正我
conjecture that human thought in the
猜想 人类的思想
brain may be a result of and now we're a
大脑可能的结果，现在我们一
massive network of highly interconnected
庞大的互联网络
neurons so from this interconnectivity
从这种互联性的神经元
emerges thought compared to artificial
与人工相比，出现了思想
neural networks we use for machine
我们用于机器的神经网络
learning today is there something
今天学习有什么
fundamentally more complex mysterious
从根本上说更复杂神秘
even magical about the biological neural
甚至神奇的生物神经
networks versus the ones we've been
网络与我们过去的网络
starting to use over the past 60 years
在过去的60年里 开始 使用
and it becomes a success in the past 10
它在过去的 10年里 取得了成功
there is something
有一些东西
a little bit mysterious about the human
关于人类 有点神秘
neural networks which is that each one
神经网络就是每一个
of us who is a neural network knows that
我们这个神经网络的人都 知道
we ourselves are conscious conscious not
我们自己是有意识的不自觉
of a sense of registering our
注册我们的感觉
surroundings or even registering our
周围甚至注册我们的
internal state but in having subjective
内部状态但具有主观性
first-person present-tense experience
第一人称现在紧张的经历
that is when I see red it's not just
那是我看到红色的时候不仅仅是
different from green but it just there's
不同于绿色， 但它 只是有
there's a redness to it I feel whether
我觉得是否有红色
an artificial system would experience
人工 系统会经历
that or not I don't know and I don't
这 或不是我不 知道 ，我不
think I can know that's why it's
想我 能 知道这就是为什么它是
mysterious if we had a perfectly
如果我们有一个完美的神秘
lifelike robot that was behaviorally
栩栩如生的机器人行为
indistinguishable from a human would we
从人没有区别，我们会
attribute consciousness to it or ought
将意识归于它或应该
we to attribute consciousness to it and
我们将意识归于它和
that's something that it's very hard to
在这个时候，这是非常难
know but putting that aside put inside
知道但撇开 这一边 往里 放
that that largely philosophical question
这主要是哲学问题
the question is is there some difference
问题是存在一些差异
between the human neural network and the
人类神经网络 与 人类之间的关系
ones that we were building in artificial
我们 在人工建造的那些
intelligence will mean that we're on the
情报将意味着我们在
current trajectory not going to reach
目前的 轨迹不会达到
the point where we've got a lifelike
我们栩栩如生的地方
robot indistinguishable from a human
机器人从 人不可区分
because the way their neural so-called
因为他们的神经所谓的方式
neural networks were organized are
神经网络组织得 很好
different from the way ours are
与我们的方式不同
organized having there's overlap but I
组织有重叠，但我
think there are some some big
认为有一些 大的
differences that they're the current
差异， 他们是当前
neural networks current so called deep
神经网络当前所谓的深层
learning systems are in reality not all
学习系统在 现实 中 并不是所有的
that deep that is they are very good at
他们非常擅长那么深
extracting high order statistical
提取高阶统计量
regularities but most of the systems
规律但大多数系统
don't have a semantic level a level of
没有一个语义级别 上水平
actual understanding of who did what to
实际了解谁做了 什么
who why where how things work what
谁为何如何运作呢？
causes what else do you think that kind
导致你认为那样的其他什么
of thing can emerge as it does so
事情 可以随着它这样做
artificial you know so much smaller the
人工， 你知道这么小
number of connections and so on in the
连接 数量 等 的
current human biological networks but do
目前的人类生物网络，但做
you think sort of go to go to
你觉得有点儿去
consciousness or to go to this higher
意识还是要走得更高
level semantic reasoning about things do
关于事物的层次语义推理
you think that can emerge with just a
你 认为只有一个可以出现
larger network with a more richly
更大的网络，更丰富
weirdly interconnected network
奇怪的互联 网络
separating consciousness because
分离 意识因为
consciousness is even a matter of
意识甚至是一个问题
complex a really good one
复杂是一个非常好的
yeah you could have you could sensibly
是的，你可以让你 理智
ask the question of whether shrimp are
问 一下虾是否是
conscious for example they're not
有意识的例如他们不是
terribly complex but maybe they feel
非常复杂，但也许他们觉得
pain so let's just put that one that
痛苦 所以， 让我们把那 一个
part of it aside yet but I think sheer
它的一部分还没有，但我认为纯粹
size of a neural network is not enough
神经网络的大小是不够的
to give it structure and knowledge but
给它结构和知识但是
if it's suitably engineered then then
如果它适当设计然后
why not
为什么不呢
that is where neural networks natural
这是神经网络自然的地方
selection did a kind of equivalent of
选择做了一种相当于
engineering of our brains so I don't
我的大脑工程所以我没有
know there's anything mysterious in the
知道这里有什么 神秘 的东西
sense that no no system made out of
感觉不是没有系统制造出来的
silicon could ever do what a human brain
硅能碍着什么人脑
can do I think it's possible in
可以做到我认为它是可能的
principle whether it'll ever happen
原则是否会发生
depends not only on how clever we are in
不仅取决于我们的聪明程度
engineering these systems but whether
设计这些系统， 但是否
even we even want to whether that's even
即使我们甚至想要这是否均匀
a sensible goal that is you can ask the
一个明智的目标 ，你可以问
question is there any locomotion system
问题是有任何运动系统
that is as as good as a human well we
这和 人类一样好
kind of want to do better than a human
有点想做 比 人 更好 的事
ultimately in terms of legged locomotion
最终在腿部运动方面
there's no reason that humans should be
人类应该没有理由
our benchmark they're their tools that
我们的基准测试他们是他们的工具
might be better in some ways it may just
可能在某些方面可能更好
be not as maybe that we can't duplicate
不要因为我们不能复制
a natural system because at some point
一个自然系统， 因为在某些时候
it's so much cheaper to use a natural
使用 天然的 便宜得多
system that we're not going to invest
我们不是要投资 系统
more brainpower and resources so for
更多的智力和资源
example we don't really have a subsidy
例如，我们实际上没有补贴
and exact substitute for wood we still
我们仍然可以替代木材
build houses out of would we still go
我们还会继续建造房屋
furniture out of wood we like the look
木头 家具 我们喜欢的样子
we like the feel it's wood has certain
我们喜欢它的木材确定的感觉
properties that synthetics don't there's
合成物不 存在的 属性
not that there's any magical or
并不是说有任何魔法或
mysterious about wood it's just that the
关于木材的神秘之处就在于它
extra steps of duplicating everything
复制一切的额外步骤
about wood is something we just haven't
关于木材是我们没有的东西
bothered because we have wood likewise a
因为我们同样拥有木材而烦恼
cotton I mean I'm wearing cotton
棉花我的意思是我穿着棉花
clothing now feels much better than the
现在的服装 感觉好多 了
polyester it's not that cotton has
聚酯不是棉花
something magic in it and it's not that
一些神奇的东西，而不是那个
if there was that we couldn't ever
如果有的话， 我们永远不可能
synthesize something exactly like cotton
合成像棉花一样的东西
but at some point it just it's just not
但在某些时候 ， 它 只是没有
worth it we've got cotton and likewise
值得一提，我们也有棉花
in the case of human intelligence the
在人类情报 的 情况下
goal of making an artificial system that
制造人造系统的目标
is exactly like the human brain is a
酷似人类的大脑 是一个
goal that we
我们的目标
no one's gonna pursue to the bitter end
没有人会 追求痛苦的结局
I suspect because if you want tools that
我怀疑， 因为如果你想要工具
do things better than humans you're not
比你做的人做得更好
going to care whether it does something
要关心它是否有所作为
like humans so for example you're
像人类一样，例如你
diagnosing cancer or particularly
诊断癌症或特别是
whether why set humans as your benchmark
是否 为什么将人类作为你的基准
but in in general I suspect you also
但总的来说我怀疑你也是
believe that even if the human should
相信即使人类应该
not be a benchmark on women's don't want
不是女性不想要的基准
to imitate humans in their system
在他们的系统中模仿人类
there's a lot to be learned about how to
关于 如何 学习 有很多东西需要 学习
create an artificial intelligence system
创建一个人工智能 系统
by studying the human yeah III think
通过研究人类耶 三世思考
that's right
没错
there in in the same way that to build
那里 以同样的方式，要建立
flying machines we want understand the
我们想要了解的飞行机器
laws of aerodynamics and including birds
空气动力学定律， 包括鸟类
but not mimic the birds right but the
但不是模仿鸟类， 而是模仿
same laws you have a view on AI
同样的法律 你 对AI 有 一个看法
artificial intelligence and safety that
人工智能和安全性
from my perspective is refreshingly
从我的角度来看，令人耳目一新
rational or perhaps more importantly has
理性的，或者更重要的是
elements of positivity to it which I
我对它的积极因素
think can be inspiring and empowering as
认为可以鼓舞人心并赋予权力
opposed to paralyzing for many people
反对许多人瘫痪
including AI researchers the eventual
最终包括AI研究人员
existential threat of AI is obvious not
人工智能的存在威胁显然不是
only possible but obvious and for many
只有可能但很明显，对许多人而言
others including a researchers the
其他人包括研究人员
threat is not obvious so Elon Musk is is
威胁并不明显，所以埃隆马斯克就是这样
famously in the highly concerned about
着名的高度关注
AI camp saying things like AI is far
AI阵营说 AI 这样的事情很远
more dangerous and nuclear weapons and
更危险的武器和核武器 和
that AI will likely destroy human
AI可能会摧毁人类
civilization so in February you said
文明所以二月你说
that if Elon was really serious about AI
如果埃隆真的认真对待AI
they the threat of AI he would stop
他们 会停止AI 的威胁
building self-driving cars that he's
建造他自己驾驶的汽车
doing very successfully as part of Tesla
作为 特斯拉的 一部分非常成功
then he said Wow if even Pinker doesn't
然后他说哇，即使Pinker没有
understand the difference between arrow
了解箭头之间的区别
AI like a car in general AI when the
人工智能就像一辆汽车一般 人工智能的时候
latter literally has a million times
后者确实有一百万次
more compute power and an open-ended
更多的计算能力和开放式的
utility function humanity is in deep
效用函数人性深入
trouble so first what did you mean by
麻烦所以首先是什么 意思
the statement about Elon Musk should
关于伊隆马斯克的声明应该
stop Bill ourselves driving cars if he's
如果他是的话，请阻止比尔自己开车
deeply concerned
深感担忧
not last time that Elon Musk has fired
不是Elon Musk上次解雇了
off an intemperate tweet well we live in
我们生活在一个不节制的推文中
a world where Twitter has power yes yeah
一个Twitter有权力的世界是的
I think the the that there are two kinds
我认为那有两种
of existential threat that have been
已存在的威胁
discussed in connection with artificial
与 人工 所讨论
intelligence and I think that they're
情报，我认为他们是
both incoherent one of them is vague
两个语无伦次 的人都很 模糊
fear of AI takeover that it just as we
害怕人工智能接管就像我们一样
subjugated animals and less
被征服的动物少了
technologically advanced people's so if
技术先进的人如此
we build something that's more advanced
我们建造更先进的东西
than us it will inevitably turn us into
比起我们，它将不可避免地使我们陷入困境
pets or slaves or or domesticated animal
宠物或奴隶或驯养动物
equivalents
当量
I think this confuses intelligence with
我认为这会混淆智力
a will to power that it so happens that
这种情况发生的意愿
in the intelligence system we are most
在我们最智能的情报系统中
familiar with namely Homo sapiens we are
我们熟悉的是智人（Homo sapiens）
products of natural selection which is a
自然选择的产品是一种
competitive process and so bundled
竞争过程如此 捆绑
together with our problem-solving
连同我们的问题解决
capacity are a number of nasty traits
能力 是一些令人讨厌的特征
like dominance and exploitation and
像统治和剥削，
maximization of power and glory and
最大化权力和荣耀
resources and influence there's no
资源和影响没有
reason to think that sheer
有理由认为纯粹
problem-solving capability will set that
问题解决能力将设定这一点
as one of its goals its goals will be
作为其目标之一， 它的目标将是
whatever we set it its goals as and as
无论我们设定它的目标是什么
long as someone isn't building a
只要有人不建立
megalomaniacal artificial intelligence
狂妄自大的人工智能
and there's no reason to think that it
并且没有理由认为它
would naturally evolve in that direction
自然 会朝那个方向发展
now you might say well what if we gave
现在你可能会说得好，如果我们给了
it the goal of maximizing its own power
它是最大化自身力量的目标
source well that's a pretty stupid goal
很好地说，这是一个 非常愚蠢的目标
to give a an autonomous system you don't
给一个你没有的自治系统
give it that goal I mean that's just
给它那个目标我的意思 是公正的
self-evident we idiotic so if you look
不言而喻 我们愚蠢如果你看
at the history of the world there's been
在世界 的历史上一直
a lot of opportunities where engineers
工程师们有很多机会
could instill in a system destructive
可以灌输一个破坏性的系统
power and they choose not to because
权力和他们选择不 因
that's the natural process of
这是的 自然过程
Engineering well weapons I mean if
工程井武器我的意思是
you're building a weapon its goal is to
您正在构建一个武器它的目标 是
destroy people and so I think they're
摧毁人民，所以我认为他们是
good reasons to not not build certain
没有建立肯定的充分理由
kinds of weapons I think the building
我认为 建筑物的各种武器
nuclear weapons was a massive mistake
核武器是 一个巨大的错误
but probably do you think so
但你可能这么 认为
maybe pause on that because that is one
也许暂停， 因为 那 是一个
of the serious threats do you think that
你认为那些严重的威胁
it was a mistake in a sense that it was
从某种意义上来说 ，这是一个错误
should have been stopped
应该已经停止了
early on or do you think it's just an
在早期或你认为它只是一个
unfortunate event of invention that this
这个发明的 不幸事件
was invented we think it's possible to
发明了我们 认为它是可能的
stop I guess is the question it's hard
停止我想这是一个 很难的问题
to rewind the clock because of course it
因为当然是倒带时钟
was invented in the context of World War
是在 第二次世界大战 的背景下 发明 的
two and the fear that the Nazis might
二，并 担心 纳粹可能
develop one first then once was
先开发一个，然后开发一个
initiated for that reason it was it it
因为这个原因而发起的就是它
was hard to turn off especially since
特别是以后很难关闭
winning the war against the Japanese and
赢得 对 日本和日本 的战争
the Nazis was such an overwhelming goal
纳粹是这样一个压倒性的目标
of every responsible person that there's
每个负责人都有
just nothing that people wouldn't have
只是 人们不会有的东西
done then to ensure victory it's quite
然后完成确保 胜利
possible if World War two hadn't
如果第二次世界大战没有
happened that nuclear weapons wouldn't
碰巧核武器不会
have been invented we can't know but I
已经发明了我们不能知道 但是我
don't think it was by any means a
不要以为它是 一种无论如何
necessity any more than some of the
必要， 而不是一些 更多
other weapon systems that were
其他武器系统
envisioned but never implemented like
设想但从未实现过像
planes that would disperse poison gas
将分散毒气的飞机
over cities like crop dusters or systems
在作物掸子或系统等城市
to try to do to create earthquakes and
试图创造地震和
tsunamis in enemy countries to weaponize
在敌国的海啸武器化
the weather weaponize solar flares all
天气武器化所有太阳耀斑
kinds of crazy schemes that that we
那种疯狂的计划，我们
thought the better off I think analogies
我认为类比更好
between nuclear weapons and artificial
核武器与人工武器之间
intelligence are fundamentally misguided
智力从根本上被误导了
because the whole point of nuclear
因为整个核点
weapons is to destroy things the point
武器是摧毁事物 的重点
of artificial intelligence is not to
人工智能 不是
destroy things so the analogy is is
摧毁事物就是这样比喻的
misleading so there's two artificial
误导所以有两个人为的
intelligence you mentioned the first one
情报你提到了第 一个
was the intelligence all know hungry
被 情报 都知道饿了
yeah the system that we design ourselves
是的， 我们自己设计的系统
where we give it the goals goals are
我们给它的目标是什么
external to the means to attain the
达到目的的手段之外
goals I if we don't design an artificial
目标我，如果我们不设计人工
intelligence system to maximize
智力系统最大化
dominance then it won't maximize
优势然后它不会最大化
dominance it just that we're so familiar
支配它只是 我们 如此熟悉
with Homo sapiens when these two traits
当这 两个特征 时， 与 智人（Homo sapiens）
come bundled together particularly in
捆绑在一起特别是在
men that we are apt to confuse high
男人，我们容易混淆高
intelligence with a will to power but
智力与权力的意志，但
that's just an error the other fear is
这只是另一个恐惧的错误
that we'll be collateral damage that
我们将受到附带损害
will give artificial intelligence a goal
将人工智能作为目标
like make paperclips and it will pursue
就像制作回形针一样 ，它会追求
that goal so brilliantly that
那个目标 如此出色
before we can stop it it turns us into
在我们阻止它之前它会把我们变成
paperclips we'll give it the goal of
回形针 我们会给它 的目标
curing cancer and it will turn us into
治愈癌症，它会把我们变成
guinea pigs for lethal experiments or
用于致死实验或豚鼠的豚鼠
give it the goal of world peace and its
给它世界和平的目标及其目标
conception of world pieces no people
世界碎片没有人概念
therefore no fighting and so it'll kill
因此没有战斗，所以 它会杀死
us all now I think these are utterly
我们所有人现在都认为这些是彻头彻尾的
fanciful in fact I think they're
实际上我认为他们是幻想
actually self-defeating they first of
实际上他们首先弄巧成拙
all assume that we're going to be so
所有人都认为我们会如此
brilliant that we can design an
辉煌，我们可以设计一个
artificial intelligence that can cure
可以治愈的人工智能
cancer but so stupid that we don't
癌症， 但 我们没有 这么愚蠢
specify what we mean by curing cancer in
详细说明治愈癌症的意思
enough detail that it won't kill us in
足够的细节， 它不会杀死 我们
the process and it assumes that the
这个过程 和它假设的
system will be so smart that it can cure
系统将 是如此智能， 它可以 治愈
cancer but so idiotic that it doesn't
癌症， 但 它是 如此愚蠢， 它没有
can't figure out that what we mean by
无法弄清楚我们的意思
curing cancer is not killing everyone so
治愈癌症并不是杀死所有人
I think that the the collateral damage
我认为是附带 损害
scenario the value alignment problem is
场景价值对齐问题是
is also based on a misconception so one
也是基于一种误解， 所以一
of the challenges of course we don't
我们 当然 没有 挑战
know how to build either system
知道如何建立任何一个系统
currently or are we even close to
目前还是我们甚至 接近
knowing of course those things can
当然知道那些事情 可以
change overnight but at this time
一夜之间改变，但 在这个 时候
theorizing about it is very challenging
理论化它是非常 具有挑战性的
in either direction so that that's
在任何一个方向， 所以那 是
probably at the core the problem is
可能是 问题 的核心
without that ability to reason about the
没有那种 推理 能力的能力
real engineering things here at hand is
真正的工程事物就在眼前
your imagination runs away with things
你的想象力随着事物而消失
exactly but let me sort of ask what do
确切但 让 我问一下是做什么的
you think was the motivation the thought
你认为这是思想的动力
process of elam Wasco i build autonomous
elam Wasco的过程我建立自主
vehicles I study autonomous vehicles I
我研究自动驾驶汽车的车辆
studied Tesla autopilot I think it is
研究特斯拉自动驾驶仪我认为是
one of the greatest currently
目前最伟大的之一
application large scale application of
应用大规模应用
artificial intelligence in the world it
人工智能的 世界里
has a potentially a very positive impact
可能会产生非常积极的影响
on society so how does a person who's
在社会 上，一个人怎么样
creating this very good quote/unquote
创造这个非常好的报价/不引用
narrow AI system also seem to be so
狭窄的人工智能系统似乎 也是如此
concerned about this other general AI
关注这个其他一般人工智能
what do you think is the motivation
你认为是什么动机
there what do you think is the thing
你觉得那是什么 东西
really you probably have to ask him but
你真的可能要问他了
there and and he is notoriously
在那里和他是出了名的
flamboyant impulsive to the as we have
华丽冲动着我们所拥有的
just seen to the detriment of his own
只是看到了他自己的损害
goals of the health of a company so I
一个公司健康的目标， 所以我
don't know what's going on
不知道发生了什么事
on his mind you probably have to ask him
在他看来，你可能不得不问他
but I don't think the and I don't think
但我不 认为我不思考
the distinction between special-purpose
特殊目的之间的区别
a and so-called general is relevant that
a和 所谓的将军是相关的
in the same way that special-purpose AI
在相同的方式， 专用 AI
is not going to do anything conceivable
不会做任何可以想象的事情
in order to attain a goal all
为了达到所有目标
engineering systems have to are designed
必须设计工程系统
to trade off across multiple goals
跨越多个目标进行权衡
well we build cars in the first place we
我们在第一时间制造汽车
didn't forget to install brakes because
不要忘记安装刹车因为
the goal of a car is to go fast it
汽车 的目标 是 加快速度
occurred to people yes you want to go
发生在人们身上是的 你想去
fast but not always so you build an
快但不总是所以 你建立一个
brakes too likewise if a car is going to
如果要开车的话 也会刹车
be autonomous that doesn't and program
是自主的，没有和编程
it to take the shortest route to the
它拿 地的最短路线
airport it's not going to take the
机场， 它不会采取
diagonal and mow down people and trees
对角线和割草人和树木
and fences because that's the shortest
和栅栏，因为 这是最短的
route that's not what we mean by the
路线不是我们所说的
shortest route when we program it and
最短路径，当我们进行编程 ，并
that's just what and an intelligent
这就是什么，一个聪明
system is by definition it takes into
根据定义它是系统
account multiple constraints the same is
帐户多个约束相同
true in fact even more true of so-called
事实上 ，所谓的更为真实
general intelligence that is if it's
一般的情报，如果是的话
genuinely intelligent it's not going to
真正聪明， 它不会
pursue some goal single-mindedly
一心一意追求目标
omitting every other consideration and
省略所有其他考虑因素
collateral effect that's not artificial
附带效应不是人为的
in general intelligence that's that's
一般情报就是这样
artificial stupidity I agree with you by
人为的愚蠢我同意你的意见
the way on the promise of autonomous
对自治的承诺的方式
vehicles for improving human welfare
改善 人类福祉的工具
I think it's spectacular and I'm
我认为这很壮观， 而且我
surprised at how little press coverage
对报道的报道很少感到惊讶
notes that in the United States alone
注意到仅在美国
something like 40,000 people die every
像 40000人死亡每
year on the highways vastly more than
高速公路上的一年远远 超过
are killed by terrorists and we spend we
被恐怖分子杀死，我们花了我们
spent a trillion dollars on a war to
花了一万亿美元用于战争
combat deaths by terrorism but half a
通过恐怖主义打击死亡， 但是半数
dozen a year whereas if you're an year
一年十二年，如果你是 一年
out 40,000 people are massacred on the
有 40,000 人被屠杀了
highways which could be brought down to
高速公路可以归结为
very close to zero so I'm with you on
非常接近零，所以我和你在一起
the humanitarian benefit let me just
人道主义利益 让我公正
mention that it's as a person who's
提到它是一个人的
building these cars it is it a little
建造这些汽车 是一 点点
bit offensive to me to say that
有点冒犯我这么说
engineers would be clueless enough not
工程师将无能为力
to engineer safety into systems I often
我 经常将安全设计到系统中
stay up at night thinking about those
熬夜思考 那些
40,000 people that are dying and
40,000人 正在死亡
everything I tried to engineer is to
我试图设计的一切 都是为了
save those people's lives so every new
拯救那些人的生命， 使每一个新的
invention that I'm super
发明我是超级的
excited about every new and the in all
对每一个新人 和所有人都感到兴奋
the deep learning literature and cvpr
深度学习文献和cvpr
conferences and nips everything I'm
会议和咬我所有的一切
super excited about is all grounded in
超级兴奋 的全部基础
making it safe and help people so I just
使它安全并帮助 人们，所以我只是
don't see how that trajectory can all a
看不出那条 轨迹 怎么样
sudden slip into a situation where
突然陷入某种情况
intelligence will be highly negative you
情报将 是非常消极的 你
know you and I certainly agree on that
认识你，我当然同意这一点
and I think that's only the beginning of
我 认为那只是 开始
the potential humanitarian benefits of
人道主义的潜在好处
artificial intelligence there's been
那里有 人工智能
enormous attention to what are we going
非常关注我们的目标
to do with the people whose jobs are
与工作的 人 一起做
made obsolete by artificial intelligence
通过人工智能过时
but very little attention given to the
但很少关注给予
fact that the jobs that hooni made
事实上， hooni所做 的工作
obsolete are horrible jobs the fact that
过时的是可怕的 工作事实
people aren't going to be picking crops
人们不会 采摘庄稼
and making beds and driving trucks and
制作床和驾驶卡车
mining coal these are you know soul
采煤这些你知道的灵魂
deadening jobs and we have a whole
减少工作，我们有一个整体
literature sympathizing with the people
文学同情人民
stuck in these menial mind deadening
陷入这些卑微的 思想中
dangerous jobs if we can eliminate them
如果我们可以消除危险的工作
this is a fantastic boon to humanity now
这是一个奇妙的恩赐给人类 现在
granted we you solve one problem and
我们解决了一个问题
there's another one namely how do we get
还有一个是我们如何得到的
these people a a decent income but if
这些人 收入不错但是如果
we're smart enough to invent machines
我们足够聪明地发明机器
that can make beds and put away dishes
可以铺床，放菜
and and handle hospital patients well I
并且很好地处理医院病人 我
think we're smart enough to figure out
我们认为我们很聪明， 可以搞清楚
how to redistribute income to apportion
如何将收入重新分配给 分摊
some of the vast economic savings to the
一些巨大的经济节约
human beings who will no longer be
不再是人类
needed to to make beds okay Sam Harris
需要把床铺好的Sam Harris
says that it's obvious that eventually
说最终很明显
AI will be in existential risk he's one
AI 会 在生存风险他的一个
of the people says it's obvious we don't
人们说很明显我们 没有
know when the claim goes but eventually
知道什么时候声称，但最终
it's obvious and because we don't know
这是显而易见的，因为我们不知道
when we should worry about it now this
什么时候我们应该担心 呢
is a very interesting argument in my
是 我的 一个非常有趣的论点
eyes so how do you how do we think about
眼睛，你怎么看我们怎么样
time scale how do we think about
时间尺度我们如何 思考
existential threats when we don't really
当我们没有真正的存在威胁时
know so little about the threat unlike
对此威胁知之甚少
nuclear weapons perhaps about this
核武器或许就此而言
particular threat that it could happen
它可能 发生的 特殊威胁
tomorrow
明天
right so but very likely won't yeah
右左右，但很可能不会 呀
they're likely to be a hundred years
他们很可能是一百年
away so how do
怎么办呢
do we ignore it do how do we talk about
我们如何忽略它我们如何 谈论它们
it do we worry about it what how do we
我们 担心它是怎么做的
think about those what is it a threat
想想 那些什么是威胁
that we can imagine it's within the
我们可以想像 它的内
limits of our imagination but not within
我们的想象极限，但没有 在
our limits of understanding - sufficient
我们的理解极限 - 足够
to accurately predict it but but what
准确地预测它，但是什么
what is what is the ether asre AI xai
什么是 以太阿雷艾 赛
being the existential threat AI can
是AI可以存在的威胁
always know like enslaving us or turning
总是知道奴役我们或转向
us into paperclips I think the most
把我们变成回形针我认为最多
compelling from the Sam Harris was fact
从 山姆哈里斯是事实 引人注目
it would be the paperclip situation yeah
这将是回形针的情况是的
I mean I just think it's totally
我的意思是我认为这完全是
fanciful I just don't build a system
幻想我只是不建立 一个系统
don't give it a don't first of all the
不要先给它一个不要的
code of engineering is you don't
您不需要工程代码
implement a system with massive control
实施一个大规模控制的系统
before testing it now perhaps the
在测试 它 之前 现在也许是
culture of engineering will radically
工程文化将从根本上说
change then I would worry I don't see
改变然后我会担心我没有看到
any signs that engineers will suddenly
工程师会突然发现任何迹象
do idiotic things like put a electrical
做愚蠢的事情，比如放电
power plant in control of a system that
电厂控制系统
they haven't tested first or all of
他们没有测试过第一次或全部
these scenarios not only imagine a
这些场景不仅仅是想象一个
almost a magically powered intelligence
几乎是神奇的动力智能
you know including things like cure
你知道包括治疗之类的东西
cancer which is probably an incoherent
癌症可能是语无伦次的
goal because there's so many different
目标， 因为有这么多不同
kinds of cancer or bring about world
各种癌症或带来 世界
peace I mean how do you even specify
和平我的意思是你怎么 指定
that as a goal but the scenarios also
作为目标，但情景也
imagine some degree of control of every
想象一下每个人的某种程度的控制
molecule in the universe which not only
宇宙 中的分子不仅如此
is itself unlikely but we would not
本身不太可能，但我们不会
start to connect these systems to
开始连接这些系统
infrastructure without without testing
没有测试的基础设施
as we would any kind of engineering
就像我们任何一种 工程
system now maybe some engineers will be
现在系统也许有些工程师会
irresponsible and we need legal and
不负责任，我们需要 合法和
regulatory and legal responsibilities
监管和法律责任
implemented so that engineers don't do
实施使工程师 不做
things that are stupid by their own
事情 由自己是愚蠢的
standards but the ii-i've never seen
标准，但 ii  - 我从未 见过
enough of a plausible scenario of
足够的合理的情景
existential threat to devote large
存在的威胁要投入大量资金
amounts of brain power to to forestall
预防脑力的数量
it so you believe in the sort of the
它让你相信 那种
power and mass of the engineering of
工程的权力和质量
reason as the argue
争辩的原因
this book of Reason science and sort of
这本理性科学 着作
be the very thing that puts the
是放的非常事
development of new technology so it's
开发新技术就是这样
safe and also keeps us safe it's the
安全， 也保证我们的安全
same and you know granted the same
同样，你知道同样的
culture of safety that currently is part
目前是安全文化的一部分
of the engineering mindset for airplanes
飞机的工程思维方式
for example so yeah I don't think that
例如，所以是的，我不这么认为
that that should be thrown out the
那应该 被扔 出去了
window and that untested all-powerful
窗户和那个未经测试的无所不能
system should be suddenly implemented
系统应该突然实施
but there's no reason to think they are
但没有理由 认为它们 是
and in fact if you look at the progress
事实上，如果 你看看进展情况
of artificial intelligence it's been you
人工智能 它一直您
know it's been impressive especially in
知道它 特别 令人印象深刻
the last ten years or so but the idea
过去的十年 左右 ，但 这个想法
that suddenly there'll be a step
突然之间会有一步
function that all of a sudden before we
在我们之前突然发挥作用
know it it will be all powerful that
知道它将是所有 强大的
there'll be some kind of recursive
会有某种递归
self-improvement some kind of Foom is
自我改善某种Foom是
also fanciful we certainly by the
也是我们当然的幻想
technology that we that were now
我们现在的技术
impresses us such as deep learning when
让我们印象深刻的 学习时间
you train something on hundreds of
你训练了数百个
thousands or millions of examples
成千上万的例子
they're not hundreds of thousands of
他们不是几 十万
problems of which curing cancer is a
治愈癌症的问题是什么
typical example and so the kind of
典型的例子等等
techniques that have allowed AI to
允许AI的技术
increase in the last five years are not
过去五年的增加不是
the claim that are going to lead to this
这会导致该索赔
fantasy of of exponential sudden
指数突然的幻想
self-improvement so it's may I think
自我改善，所以我想
it's it's kind of a magical thinking
这是一种 神奇的想法
it's not based on our understanding of
它不是基于我们的 理解
how AI actually works now give me a
AI如何实际工作 现在给我一个
chance here so you said fanciful magical
在这里的机会，所以你说幻想神奇
thinking in his TED talk Sam Harris says
在他的TED演讲中思考Sam Harris说
that thinking about AI killing all human
考虑人工智能杀死所有人类
civilization is somehow fun
文明在某种程度上很有趣
intellectually now I have to say as a
智力上现在我不得不说
scientist engineer I don't find it fun
科学家工程师我觉得不好玩
but when I'm having beer with my non-ai
但是当我和我的 非ai 喝啤酒的时候
friends there is indeed something fun
朋友确实有些有趣
and appealing about it like talking
和谈话一样 吸引人
about an episode of black mirror
关于黑 镜的 一集
considering if a large meteor is headed
考虑是否有一颗大流星
towards Earth we were just told a large
对地球我们只是被告知一个大的
meteors headed towards Earth something
流星走向地球的东西
like this
像这样
and can you relate to this sense of fun
你能谈谈这种有趣的感觉吗？
and do you understand the psychology of
和你懂的心理学
it yeah that's a good question
是的，那是一个很好的问题
III personally don't find it fun
三， 个人不觉得好玩
I find it kind of actually a waste of
我发现它实际上是浪费
time because there are genuine threats
时间因为有真正的威胁
that we ought to be thinking about like
我们应该考虑的事情
like pandemics like like a cyber
喜欢像网络一样的流行病
security vulnerabilities like the
像这样的安全漏洞
possibility of nuclear war and certainly
核战争的 可能性 当然
climate change this is enough to film it
气候变化这足以 拍摄它
many conversations without and I think
没有和我想的很多对话
there I think Sam did put his finger on
在那里，我认为山姆确实把手指放在了
something namely that there is a
什么东西， 即 有一个
community us sometimes called the
社区我们有时称为
rationality community that delights in
喜欢的理性社区
using its brain power to come up with
利用它的脑力来提出
scenarios that would not occur to mere
不会发生的情景
mortals to less cerebral people so there
凡人少脑子那么
is a kind of intellectual thrill in
是一种智力刺激
finding new things to worry about that
找到新事物要担心
no one has worried about yet
没有人担心
I actually think though that it's not
我实际上认为它 不是
only is it is a kind of fun that doesn't
只是 它是一种没有的乐趣
give me particular pleasure but I think
给我特别的乐趣， 但我想
there is there can be a pernicious side
可能会有一个有害的一面
to it namely that you overcome people
它就是你克服了人
with such dread such fatalism that
这样的恐惧这种宿命论是
there's so many ways to die to
死亡的方式有很多种
annihilate our civilization that we may
消灭我们可能的文明
as well enjoy life while we can there's
我们可以享受生活
nothing we can do about it if climate
什么我们可以做些 什么 ，如果气候
change doesn't do us in then runaway
改变不会让我们 失控
robots will so let's enjoy ourselves now
机器人将让我们现在享受自己
we've got to prioritize we have to look
我们必须优先考虑我们必须要看
at threats that are close to certainty
在接近确定的威胁下
such as climate change and distinguish
如气候变化 和区分
those from ones that are merely
来自那些仅仅是那些
imaginable but with infinitesimal
可以想象， 但有无穷小
probabilities and we have to take into
概率，我们必须考虑
account people's worry budget you can't
帐户人的担心预算 你不能
worry about everything and if you so
担心一切，如果你这样做
dread and fear and terror and numb and
恐惧，恐惧和恐惧， 麻木和麻木
fatalism it can lead to a kind of
宿命论它可以导致 一种
numbness well they're just these
麻木很好，他们 只是这些
problems are overwhelming and the
问题是压倒性的
engineers are just gonna kill us all so
工程师们只是会杀了我们 那么 所有
let's either destroy the entire
让我们破坏整个
infrastructure of science technology or
科学技术 或基础设施
let's just enjoy life while we can so
让我们尽情享受生活吧
there's a certain line of worry which
有一线 担心
I'm worried about a lot of things
我很担心很多 事情
engineering there's a certain line of
工程有 一定的
worry when you cross a lot across
当您在穿越了很多烦恼
that it becomes paralyzing fear as
它变得瘫痪恐惧
opposed to productive fear and that's
反对生产恐惧，那就是
kind of what they're highlighting there
他们在那里强调的 那种
exactly right and we've seen some we
完全正确， 我们已经看到了一些我们
know that human effort is not well
知道人的努力并不好
calibrated against risk in that because
由于这个因素而对风险进行了校准
a basic tenet of cognitive psychology is
认知心理学的基本原则是
that perception of risk and hence
风险 以及因此 这种 看法
perception of fear is driven by imagined
对恐惧的感知是由想象所驱动的
ability not by data and so we miss
能力不是数据，所以 我们想念
allocate vast amounts of resources to
分配大量的资源来
avoiding terrorism which kills on
避免恐怖主义的杀戮
average about six Americans a year with
平均大约一年 有 六个美国人
a one exception of 9/11 we invade
我们入侵 911事件的一个例外
countries we invent entire new
我们发明全新的国家
departments of government with massive
有大规模的政府部门
massive expenditure of resources and
大量的资源和支出
lives to defend ourselves against a
为了保护自己而生活
trivial risk whereas guaranteed risks
琐碎的风险， 而保证风险
and you mentioned as one of them you
你提到了其中一个 你
mentioned traffic fatalities and even
提到交通事故死亡人数甚至
risks that are not here but are
风险不在这里， 但是
plausible enough to worry about
似乎有点担心
like pandemics like nuclear war receive
像核战争那样的流行病收到
far too little attention the in
太少关注了
presidential debates there's no
总统辩论没有
discussion of how to minimize the risk
讨论如何 将风险 降至最低
of nuclear war lots of discussion of
核战争的大量讨论
terrorism for example and and so we I
以恐怖主义为例，我们也是如此
think it's essential to calibrate our
认为校准 我们的工作至关重要
budget of fear worry concern planning to
恐惧预算担心计划到
the actual probability of harm yep so
伤害的实际概率 是如此
let me ask this then this question
让我问一下 这个 问题
so speaking of imagined ability you said
所以谈到你说的想象能力
it's important to think about reason and
思考理性和思考是很重要的
one of my favorite people who who likes
我最喜欢的人之一
to dip into the outskirts of reason
浸入理性的郊区
through fascinating exploration of his
通过引人入胜的探索 他的
imagination is Joe Rogan oh yes you so
想象力是Joe Rogan哦是的 你就是这样
who has through reason used to believe a
谁有理由过去相信一个
lot of conspiracies and through a reason
很多阴谋和通过一个理由
has stripped away a lot of his beliefs
已经剥夺了他的许多信仰
in that way so it's fascinating actually
以 这种方式， 所以它真的很吸引人
to watch him through rationality kind of
通过理性观察他
throw away that ideas of Bigfoot and
抛弃大脚怪的想法
9/11 I'm not sure exactly trails I don't
9/11我不确定我不知道的确切 路径
know what the leaves in yet
知道叶子还在
but you no longer know believed in
但你不再相信了
that's right no either he's become a
这是对的，他也不会 成为一个
real force for for good yeah so you were
真正的力量，因为 你是 好的
on the Joe Rogan podcast in February and
在二月和二月的Joe Rogan播客
had a fascinating conversation but as
有一个迷人的谈话，但作为
far as I remember didn't talk much about
我记得并没有多说什么
artificial intelligence I will be on his
人工智能 我会在他身上
podcast in a couple weeks
几周播客
Joe is very much concerned about
乔非常关心
existential threat away I am not sure if
存在的威胁远离我不确定是否
you're this is why I was I was hoping
你就是这就是我希望的原因
that you would get into that topic and
你会 进入 那个话题
in this way he represents quite a lot of
通过这种方式，他代表了很多
people who look at the topic of AI from
人 谁看AI从话题
10,000 foot level so as an exercise of
10,000英尺的 水平，以便 锻炼身体
communication he said it's important to
沟通他说这很重要
be rational and reason about these
是理性的， 推理 这些
things let me ask if you were to coach
事情让我问你是否要去教练
me as AI researcher about how to speak
我是AI研究员，讲的是如何说话
to Joe and the general public about AI
乔和公众 关于AI
what would you advise well I'd the short
你会给 我 什么建议 我做的简短
answer would be to read the sections
答案是阅读各节
that I wrote an Enlightenment I know
我写了一个我知道的启蒙运动
about AI but a longer reason would be I
关于AI，但 较长的理由是 我
think to emphasize and I think you're
想强调，我 想你是
very well positioned as an engineer to
非常适合作为工程师
remind people about the culture of
提醒 人们关于文化的
engineering that it really is safety
工程，它确实是 安全的
oriented that another discussion in
面向另一个讨论
enlightenment now I plot rates an
启示我现在绘制费率
accidental death from various causes
各种原因造成的意外死亡
plane crashes car crashes Occupational
飞机 坠毁车祸 职业
accidents even death by lightning
事故甚至被闪电致死
strikes and they all plummet because the
罢工，他们都直线下降，因为
culture of engineering is how do you
工程的文化是怎么做的 ，你
squeeze out the the lethal risks death
挤出死亡致命的风险
by fire death by drowning death by
死于溺水死亡的死亡
asphyxiation all of them drastically
所有这些都严重窒息
declined because of advances in
由于进步而下降
engineering then I gotta say I did not
工程然后我得说我没有
appreciate until I saw those graphs and
欣赏，直到我看到那些图表 和
it is because exactly people like you
这是因为人们喜欢你
who stamp at night thing oh my god it is
谁在晚上的事情戳噢，我的上帝， 它是
what a mime is what I mean what I'm
什么是哑剧是我的意思我是 什么
inventing likely to hurt people and to
发明了可能伤害人民 和
deploy ingenuity to prevent that from
部署聪明才智以防止这种情况发生
happening now I'm not an engineer
现在发生我不是工程师
although I spent 22 years at MIT so I
虽然我在麻省理工学院度过了22年，所以我
know something about the culture of
了解一些文化
engineering my understanding is that
工程学我的理解是
this is the way this is what you think
这就是 你的 想法
if you're an engineer
如果 你是一名工程师
and it's essential that that culture not
而且这种文化不是必不可少的
be suddenly switched off when come start
当来开始 突然关闭
official intelligence so I mean fact
官方情报所以我的意思是事实
that could be a problem but is there any
这可能是一个问题，但有任何问题
reason to think it would be switched off
有理由 认为 它会被关闭
I don't think so and one there's not
我不这么认为，而且没有
enough engineers speaking up for this
足够的工程师为此发表意见
way for this the excitement for the
为此而兴奋的方式
positive view of human nature what
人性的积极看法是什么
you're trying to create is the
你想打造 的 是
positivity like everything we try to
积极就像我们尝试一切
invent is trying to do good for the
发明正在努力做的好了
world but let me ask you about the
世界， 但让 我问你 关于
psychology of negativity it seems just
看似公正的消极心理学
objectively not considering the topic it
客观上没有 考虑它的主题
seems that being negative about the
似乎对此持否定态度
future makes you sound smarter than me
未来让你听起来比我聪明
positive about the future irregardless
积极关于未来无论如何
of topic am I correct in the observation
题目我在观察纠正
and if you if so why do you think that
如果你这样做，你为什么这么认为呢？
is yeah I think that I think there is
是的，我认为我认为有
that that phenomenon that as Tom Lehrer
就像Tom Lehrer那样的现象
the satirist said always predict the
讽刺作家说总是预测
worst and you'll be hailed as a prophet
最糟糕的，你会被称为先知
it may be part of our overall negativity
它可能是我们整体消极情绪的一部分
bias we are as a species more attuned to
偏见我们是一个更适应的物种
their negative than the positive we
他们的消极而不是积极的我们
dread losses more than we enjoy gains
恐惧损失超过我们享受的收益
and that mate might open up a space for
而这个 伙伴可能会 开辟一片空间
prophets to remind us of harms and risks
先知提醒我们危害和风险
and losses that we may have overlooked
和我们可能忽略的损失
so I think there there there is that
所以我觉得 那里有
asymmetry so you've written some of my
不对称所以你写了一些我的
favorite books all over the place so
最喜欢的书籍到处 都是
starting from enlightenment now to the
从启蒙开始到现在
better angels of our nature
更好的天使
blank slate how the mind works the the
空白的板岩是如何运作 的
one about language language instinct
一个关于语言语言的本能
bill gates big fan to set of your most
比尔门大风扇 设置你 最
recent book that it's my new favorite
最近的一本书 ，这是我的 新宠
book of all time so for you as an author
所有时间的书， 所以 作为作者你
what was the book early on in your life
你生命中的 早期书是什么？
that had a profound impact on the way
这 对 道路 产生了深远的 影响
you saw the world certainly this book
你看世界肯定是这本书
enlightenment now is influenced by David
启蒙现在受到大卫的影响
Deutsch as the beginning of infinity a
德意志作为 无限 的开始 a
rather deep reflection on knowledge and
对知识和知识的深刻反思
the power of knowledge to improve the
知识 的力量 来改善
human condition the and with bits of
人类的条件和有点
wisdom such as that problems are
诸如问题之类的智慧
inevitable but problems are solvable
不可避免但问题是可以解决的
given the
鉴于
knowledge and that solutions create new
知识和解决方案创造新的
problems have to be solved in their turn
问题必须轮流解决
that's I think a kind of wisdom about
这就是我想 对 一种智慧
the human condition that influenced the
是影响人类生存条件
writing of this book there's some books
写这本书有一些书
that are excellent but obscure some of
一些优秀而又模糊不清的东西
which I have on my page of my website I
我在我的网站页面上有 我
read a book called the history of force
读了一本名为“ 武力 史” 的书
self-published by a political scientist
由政治学家自己出版
named James Payne on the historical
名叫詹姆斯佩恩的历史
decline of violence and that was one of
暴力的减少， 这是其中之一
the inspirations for the better angels
对更好的天使 的灵感
of our nature
我们的天性
the what about early on if we look back
如果我们回顾一下，那么早期的事情
when you're maybe a teenager loved a
当你或许是一个十几岁的时候，你很喜欢
book called one two three infinity when
这本书叫一二三无限时
I was a young adult I read that book by
我是一个年轻的成年人，我读过那本书
George gamma the physicist very
乔治· 伽马物理学家非常
accessible in humorous explanations of
在幽默的解释访问
relativity of number theory of
数论的相对论
dimensionality high multiple dimensional
维数高维多维
spaces in a way that I think is still
我认为仍然是一种空间
delightful seventy years after it was
这是令人愉快的七十年
published I like that the time life
发表我喜欢的时间生活
science series these were books that
科学系列这些都是书籍
would arrive every month my mother
我妈妈每个月 都会到
subscribed to each one on a different
订阅了不同的每一个
topic one would be on electricity what
话题一是 电力什么的
would be on forests want to be learned
会想要学习森林
may evolution and then one was on the
5月进化，然后一个是 在
mind and I was just intrigued that there
心灵和我只是那里的好奇心
could be a science of mind and that that
可能是一种心灵科学
book I would cite as an influence as
我会引用一本影响作为
well then later on you fell in love with
那么后来你就 爱上 了
the idea of studying the mind that's one
研究心灵的想法是 一个
thing that grabbed you it was one of the
抓住你的 东西是其中之一
things I would say the I read as a
我会说我读到的东西
college student the book reflections on
大学生书中的思考
language by Noam Chomsky spent most of
诺姆乔姆斯基的语言花费了大部分时间
his career here at MIT Richard Dawkins
他在麻省理工学院理查德道金斯的职业生涯
two books the blind watchmaker and The
盲人制表师和The
Selfish Gene or enormous Li influential
自私的基因或巨大的 李有影响力
partly for mainly for the content but
部分主要是针对内容而且
also for the writing style the ability
也为 写作风格 的能力
to explain abstract concepts in lively
生动地解释抽象概念
prose Stephen Jay Gould first collection
散文Stephen Jay Gould首次收藏
ever since Darwin also excellent example
自达尔文以来 也是出色的 榜样
of lively writing George Miller
活泼的写作乔治米勒
psychologist that most psychologists are
心理学家 ，大多数心理学家
familiar with came up with the idea that
熟悉了想 出来的想法
human memory has a capacity of seven
人类记忆的容量为7
plus or minus two chunks and then
加上或减去两个块 然后
Sophia's biggest claim to fame but he
索菲亚最大的声誉， 但他
wrote a couple of books on language and
写了几本关于语言和书籍的书
communication that I've read it's an
我读过的通讯是一个
undergraduate again beautifully written
大学生再次精美的写作
and intellectually deep wonderful Steven
和智慧深刻的精彩史蒂文
thank you so much for taking the time
非常感谢您抽出宝贵时间
today my pleasure thanks a lot Lex
今天，我非常感谢Lex
you
您